我不知你感觉怎样 但我好紧张
I don't know about you,but I'm nervous.
吉祥如意!
Mazel tov!
吉祥如意 早生贵子
Mazel tov! Many children.
这是件大喜事 roz
This is a great thing,roz.
我真为你高兴
I am so happy for you.
谢谢 Silver太太
Thank you,mrs. Silver.
Yonatan是个出身良好的好男人
Yonatan is a good man from a good family.
我知道你为我细心挑选的
I know you chose well for me.
我好有福气
I've been blessed.
跨物种恋爱
Cross-species mating.
倘若你喜欢达尔文和加拉帕戈斯群岛的话
If you like darwin and the galapagos.
Amber和我有许多共同点
Amber and i have a lot in common.
她是蛇蝎女
She's a cutthroat bitch.
你看"黑暗的胜利"都会哭
You cry over dark victory.
Bette davis 也是个强硬武断的女人/(Bette davis是"黑暗的胜利"的女主演)
Bette davis,another/strong,assertive woman.
你不喜欢强硬 或是武断/你喜欢可怜兮兮亟需援助
You don't like strong. You don't/like assertive.You like needy.
她不会快要死了吧?
She's not dying,is she?
什么 滚开
Yes. Go away.
我看最多撑两个月
I give it two months.
赌100美金
Hundred bucks.
不怎么公平
Not really fair.
你立场不客观
You're not objective.
- 而我只不过想教育-/- 我们已经交往四个月了
- But I'm all about the/teaching- - we're at four months.
你瞒我?
You hid this from me?
我错了还不行么?
I was wrong,okay?
我以为你会生气
I thought you'd be upset.
我以为你会在走廊里追踪我--
I thought you'd track/me down in hallways--
我真不该忽略了床第一事
I shouldn't have discounted the sex.
她柔软灵巧/所以你俩关系能推迟两个月崩溃
She's obviously limber enough to/put off the meltdown for two months.
她并不可怜兮兮
She's not needy.
我也不需要可怜兮兮的人
I don't need needy.
她张牙舞爪
She's scary.
张牙舞爪怎么会需要可怜呢?
Why does scary need pathetic?
你打算去跟她谈吗?
Are you gonna talk to her?
我没有别的选择
I don't see that I have any choice.
你没意见?
You all right with that?
没有从我手里拯救她的冲动?
No impulse to save her from me?
我打破了固有模式 House
I've broken the pattern,House.
所以这才有机会发生
Which is why this has a chance.
我明白你总会心存疑虑
I know you're too suspicious to accept/that without getting out your ruler,
不用尺子 卡钳和扫描仪检查一番的话/你不会接受
and your calipers,and your/scanning equipment,so...
那就去吧
go ahead.
用你那一套去探个究竟吧
Get it out of your system.
38岁女性膀胱失控 尿血
38-year-old female with loss of/bladder control,blood in her urine,
还有在婚礼上昏倒跌落 腿骨折
and a broken leg from/collapsing at her wedding.
尿路感染打氨苄青霉素
Ampicillin for the uti.
断腿打磨光石膏
Shiny cast for the leg.
你们知道Wilson和Amber约会吗?
You guys know Wilson's dating Amber?
不知道
No.
- Wilson 和 Amber/- 我早知道了
- Wilson and Amber/- I knew.
我那时想约她出去呢
I asked her out.
她说刚开始和某人交往
Said she'd just started seeing someone.
检测尿路感染的细菌培养是阴性的
cultures were negative for utis.
过往没有创伤和性病史
No signs of previous trauma or stds.
肾癌
Kidney cancer.
Ct扫描没有发现肿瘤或肾结石
Ct was clean for tumors/and kidney stones.
我还以为Amber吓到你们了呢
I thought Amber scared you guys.
她确实
She does.
但她会徒步去加拿大
But she also has legs that/go all the way up to canada.
加拿大人也会--/并不意味我想和其中某个约会
So do canadians--doesn't/mean I wanna date one.
她低钠--可能是膀胱内膜异位
Her sodium's low--could be/endometriosis in the bladder.
低钠也有可能因为食物摄取少
Low sodium could also be from low food.
哈西德派的犹太人在婚礼日禁食
Hasidic jews fast on their wedding day.
或是她体内的某种毒素吸取了钠
Or sodium was absorbed by a/toxin already in her system.
是因为徒步 还是你感受到她的灵魂?
Was it just the legs,or did you/detect something resembling a soul?
她对我的影响逐渐加深
She grew on me.
如果她体内有毒素 可能是酚
If there's a toxin in/her,could be carbolic acid.
我现在说的是病人
I'm talking about the patient now.
那么多的酚 该是有人对她下毒
That much carbolic acid,someone/would have had to poison her.
还可能是哥萨克人呢--
Could have/been a cossack--
如果是在18世纪的波兰/而哥萨克人爱喝家用清洁剂的话
if this was 18th century poland and/cossacks were into household cleansers.
更可能的是 中毒者就是下毒者
Which is why it's more likely/that the poisoner was poisonee.
自杀是犯罪
Suicide's a sin.
从"人们撒谎" 推导出 "人们造罪"
Corollary of "people/lie" is "people sin."
在我的世界里 人们包括犹太人
And in my world,people includes jews.
她正准备结婚
She was getting married.
哈西德派女人结婚早/以便早生小哈西德人
Hasidic women marry young so they can/start pushing out little hasidilings.
38岁结婚 意味着剩女被推给了剩男
38 means a woman not on anyone's hot list being/pushed onto a guy who's not on anyone's hot list.
无路可逃啊 走投无路
No way out,no way out.
膀胱内膜异位/比罔测她的人生没意义更合理
Endometriosis fits better than an/epiphany that her life is meaningless.
应该用芳香化酶抑制剂 做膀胱内镜确认
We should start her on A.I.S/and do a cystoscopy to confirm.
检查她内脏里不良细胞/去她家查因果报应
Fine,check her innards for bad/cells and her home for bad karma.
酚该是放在后悔和自我厌恶旁边的架子上
Carbolic acid should be on the shelf right/next to the regret and the self-loathing.
这些人都疯了
These people are crazy.
是啊 她就该憎恨自己
Yeah. She should be self-hating.
我不憎恨自己
I'm not self-hating.
我恨脱离现实的宗教信徒
I hate religious people who/are out of touch with reality.
要是对象没什么大毛病/见面三次就结婚了
You only marry someone you met three/times if they're carrying a little mistake.
他们的离婚率怎么样?
What's their divorce rate?
清洁剂全是有机的
Cleaners are all organic.
都不含酚
Nothing with carbolic acid.
你喜欢他们看对眼的方式?
You like how they hook up?
浪漫不过是感情上的前戏
Romance is just emotional foreplay.
烛光晚餐 鲜花
Candlelight meals,flowers.
和宗教仪式大同小异
It's as much a ritual as/anything these people do.
何不找个和你志同道合的人?
Why not go with someone who's/pre-vetted,shares the same values?
直截了当
Cut to the quick.
价值观也许是大方向/但共度时光才能让你了解细节--
Values may give you the big picture,but/time together gives you the little picture--
她吃饭是不是太大声?
does she chew her food too loud?
她能不能让你安心看球
Will she leave you alone/during the final four?
承诺越深/就越容易忽略叫人惊讶的小毛病
You commit to something deeper,you/let the little surprises slide.
惊讶是致命的--/所以直到不再惊讶了我才承诺
Surprises kill-- which is why I only/commit when there are no more surprises.
看来你对妻子已经不会惊讶了
And you have no more/surprises for your wife.
你觉得这该出现在第二次约会吗?
Do you think this came/upon date number two?
你听说过哈西德派犹太人从事硬摇滚吗?
You ever heard of a/hasidic jew into hard rock?
她是这些专辑的制作人
She's listed as a/producer on all of these.
哪里有摇滚和性爱...
Where there's rock and roll,and sex...
通常哪里就有毒品
usually,there's drugs.
我是回头的浪子
I'm baal teshuvah.
我大约6个月前加入哈西德派的
I became hasidic about six months ago.
在这六个月前呢?
And before six months ago?
音乐事业并不以神圣著称
Music business isn't exactly/known for its holiness.
海洛因
Heroin.
但我已经戒了几个月了
But I've been clean for months.
Yonatan知道
Yonatan knows.
大体情况
The broad strokes.
他从没真正问过细节
He never actually asks the details.
说重要的是我的现在 而不是过去
Says what's important is the person/that I am now,not the person I was then.
- 你是怎么一路从-/- 只是上一次辅导课
- How do you go all the way/from- - just took a class.
接着是另一次辅导课
Then I took another class.
你就这么彻底离开音乐事业了?
And you just completely/left the music business?
流行音乐被认为是轻浮的
Pop music is considered frivolous.
同样的理由我们也不看电视和电影
Same reason we don't/watch tvor go to movies.
使用毒品可能会造成长期损害
Your drug use may have/caused some long-term damage.
我们要取头发样本测试潜伏的毒素
We're gonna need to take a hair/sample to test for latent toxins.
那你再也不能看星球大战了
So you can never watch star wars again.
你琢磨只要答应甩掉Wilson 我就会雇你
You figured that I'll hire you/if you promise to dump Wilson.
- 你是怎么-/- Wilson有钥匙
- How did you- -/Wilson had a key.
你想好了 一开始会被我整
You figure that I'll make/your life hell at first,
但最终我会发现你的好处 就会留下你
but I'll eventually see how/good you are and keep you.
是个不错的计划 你不觉得吗?
It's a good plan,don't you think?
针对你量身定做
Perfectly tailored to your personality.
不 不是
No,it's not.
你知道不是的
You know it's not.
说明你只是想留在我的生活圈里
Means you just wanna stay in my orbit.
你觉得最终我会意识到自己犯了错
'Cause you figureI'll/eventually realize that
你就能当面羞辱我
I made a mistake and you're/gonna be able to rub my face in it.
我都等不及了
I can't wait.
肯定特棒
It's gonna be awesome.
不 也不是
No,it's not.
你知道不会
And you know it's not.
因为你知道即使我错了 也绝不会承认
'Cause you know that even if I made a/mistake,I'd never admit that I made a mistake.
说明你只是通过玩弄Wilson来玩弄我
Which means that you're just/toying with Wilson to toy with me.
你的目的是单纯的凶猛复仇
Your goal is pure feral vengeance.
为了更大的利益 只能牺牲无辜的旁观者
Innocent bystander,but/there'sa greater good.
不 才不会呢
No,that's not it.
因为燃着了的大便袋不会朝旁观者投
Because a bag of flaming/poop bypasses the bystander.
所以...
So...
是哪个呢 House?
which is it,House?
我这么做是为你呢...
Am I in this for you...
还是为他?
or am I in this for him?
把他的运动衫还给他
Give him back his sweatshirt.
劝你不要再伪装了
Pit stains don't become you.
治疗没有作用 排除了内膜异位
Treatment had no effect./Rules out endometriosis.
头发残留毒品是阴性
And her hair sample was/negative for residue drugs.
这女人生活放纵 直至6个月前
This woman lived in the fast/lane till six months ago.
也许我们漏了什么
Maybe we're missing something.
她承认使用了毒品
She admitted drug use.
难道要怀疑 她隐瞒了曾做过石棉矿工
Doubt she's holding out on/her days as an asbestos miner.
冷球蛋白血症能解释这些症状
Cryoglobulinemia might/account for the symptoms.
除了你忽略的那个症状
Except for the one you missed.
她的状况没有变化
there's no change in her condition.
我说的不是一个新症状
I'm not talking about a new symptom.
我说的是六个月前出现的那个
I'm talking about one that/presented six months ago.
她是个疯子/但也不能给她10cc无神论 就遣她回家
Look,she's nuts,but we can't just give/her 10 ccs of atheismand send her home.
宗教是狂热的信仰 无依据的希望
Religion is a symptom of irrational/belief and groundless hope.
而精神状态改变是卟啉病的表症
Altered mental status,on the other/hand,is a symptom of porphyria.
她没有表现出无法控制的愤怒 哭泣 焦虑
She didn't develop uncontrollable/anger,crying,anxiety.
她只是决定去教堂
She just decided to go to temple.
这女人不只是选择遵从犹太饮食教规
The woman didn't just/choose to keep kher.
她直接跳到了极端的哈西德主义/生活在严苛的教规下
She went directly to the extremes of/hasidism,a life of stringent rules.
她变成了受虐狂
She became a masochist.
她不喜欢旧生活 所以改变了
She didn't like her old/life,so she changed it.
人不会改变
People don't change.
他们想变 他们需要
They want to. They need to.
Taub放弃了6位数收入的整形事业/选择这份工作
Taub gave up a six figure plastic/surgery career for this job.
说明他也得了卟啉病?
That mean he has porphyria?
他换工作是为了挽救婚姻
He switched jobsto save his marriage.
这么做是避免改变
He did it to avoid change.
他是对的
He's right.
除非突然疯了 你不能突然决定疯掉
You don't suddenly choose crazy/without suddenly being crazy.
不不 如果她突然出走去玩低空跳伞/或与猩猩共同生活
No,no,if she walked away from everything/to go base jumping or live with apes,
我们不会进行这场讨论的
we wouldn't be having this discussion.
我们会的 谁让她超兴奋的膀胱滴血了
We would if she was also tinkling/blood out of her over excited bladder.
给她放血 抽血色素
Pump hadassah full of/hematin and give her a phlebotomy.
放血?
bloodletting?
卟啉病是一种罕见的遗传失调/过度生产特定蛋白
porphyria is a rare genetic disorder that/causes an overproduction of a certain protein.
放血缓解--
Draining the/bloodrelieves--
用头发检测毒品损害显示她有罕见的基因病?
the hair test for damage from drugs/showed she has a rare genetic disease?
不--不全是
Not--not/exactly.
我们正在做确认测试
We're testing her now to confirm.
你们还没确认就治疗?
You're treating it before you confirm it?
血液检查结果要等24小时
Blood test results take 24 hours.
你们肯定发现什么 才会有此怀疑
You must have seen something that/makes you suspect it.
House医生有个理论
Dr. House has a theory.
基于什么的理论?
A theory based on what?
我们想换医生
We'd like a different doctor.
我向您保证 House医生是最好的
I assure you that dr./House is our best--
那我可以接受仅次于他的医生
then we will settle for second-best,
不要把我妻子的病因归咎于她的宗教就行
someone who doesn't think my wife/is sick just because she's religious.
要是你乐意 我还有另一个诊断/仅次于最佳哦
If you prefer,I can give your/wife my second-best diagnosis.
你知道Wilson在和Amber约会吗?
Do you know Wilson's dating Amber?
我已经看过病历了
I have reviewed the chart.
你的某个手下认为/冷球蛋白血症同样符合病人的症状
Someone on your team must have pointed out/that cryoglobulinemia also fits the symptoms.
是啊 符合的症状多了
Yes,it fits many of the symptoms.
我妻子的身体有病
My wife's body is sick.
但她的思想和灵魂很健康
Her mind and soul are fine.
- 你一直都恪守上帝的600条戒律 对吗?/- 613条
You live according to/god's 600 commandments,right?
你全部都理解吗?
You understand them all?
活到老 学到老...
Takes a lifetime of learning...
一部分是你理解并认同的/所以其余的就算不理解也照样遵守
but you follow the ones you don't understand/because the ones you do understand make sense,
你相信上帝制定戒律 他心中自有分寸
and you believe the guy who/created them knows what he's doing.
当然了
Of course.
所以你得相信我的诊断 让我着手治疗
So you will trust my diagnosis/and you'll let me treat her,
因为在这间神寺 我就是上帝
because in this temple, I am dr. Yahweh.
我要求换一个医生
I want a new doctor.
我去给她上吲哚美辛/就按冷球蛋白血症来治
I'm stting her on indomethacin/for cryoglobulemia.
人是不会改变的
People don't change.
比如我就会一直重复 "人是不会改变的"
For example,I'm gonna/keep repeating: People don't change.
所以根本不存在经治疗而戒瘾的酗酒者?
So alcoholics that successfully/go through treatment don't exist.
照样是酒鬼
They're still alcoholics.
如果他们到死都没有再喝上一杯
If they never take a/drink as long as they live,
那是因为他们活得不够久
it's only 'cause they/didn't live long enough.
如果对自己的生活不满/精神健全的人都会寻求改变
If you're dissatisfied with your/life,changing it is a symptom of mental health.
我明白 你很难理解这个道理
I get why that concept is strange to you.
氧和度85  她缺氧
O2 sats are 85. She's hypoxic.
可能需要插管
We might need to intubate.
她怎么回事?
What's wrong with her?
绝对不是冷球蛋白血症
It's definitely not cryoglobulinemia.
去问上帝吧
Better ask him.
给她输了整晚的氧气
we kept her on oxygen overnight.
现在呼吸已经稳定 氧和度也回升到95
Her respiratory rate stabilized,and/her o-sat's back up to 95.
我今早看见Amber送Wilson来上班
I saw Amber drop off Wilson this morning.
是啊 都是男人开车送女人的啦
Yes,the male always drives the female.
呼吸问题是由什么导致的呢?
So what caused the breathing problem?
肺部问题说明不是卟啉症
pulmonary involvement rules/out porphyria.
谁主动去吻别的?
She kiss him or he kiss her?
没看到
I missed it.
那个戴舌钉的实验室技术员正好也在停车
The lab tech with the/tonguestud also pulled up.
韦格纳病可以解释血沉速率的升高
Wegener's would explain her/elevated sed rate.
韦格纳病不能解释精神状态的改变
Wegener's wouldn't explain the/changed mental status.
其实我们不信服白板上的那行字
Actually,we've been trying to/ignore that part of the whiteboard.
我是用黑笔写的
I wrote it in black.
我用黑笔的时候可都是很认真的
I'm always serious when I use black.
- 红斑狼疮可以解释.../- 也许她没有改变呢
- Lupus would explain- -/maybe she didn't change.
你是同意我呢 还是另有想法?
Are you agreeing with/me or you making a point?
另有想法
I'm making a point.
这下有的耗了
That's gonna take longer.
我们怎么知道现在的Roz是伪装的/她以前是怎么样的人?
How do we know that the real roz isn't/who she is now and who she was then?
难道仅仅因为她的过去是真实的/就断定她的现在是虚伪的吗?
Can't we say that her previous life was/true without making her present one a fraud?
"生活是一团麻" 很好
"Life is messy" argument. Nice.
说了等于白说
Explains everything/without explaining anything.
如果是红斑狼疮 那心脏可能会有问题
If it's lupus,there's a heart/problem we don't know about yet.
给她做应激测试
Run her through a stress test.
如果发生心脏病 我就是对的
If she has a heart attack,I'm right.
或者也可以等等 也许...
Or we could/wait,hope that--
你担心她会发生心脏病
you're afraid to give her a heart attack.
- 当然担心了/- 没理由担心
- Of course we're afraid-/- no reason to be afraid.
除非你觉得我是对的
Unless you think I'm right.
是韦格纳病
It's wegener's.
但我们会准备急救车 以防万一
But we'll have the/crash cart just in case.
哦 我的天!
Oh,my god!
你们俩怎么也在?
What are you guys doing here?
突然间我很想凑热闹
I had a sudden yen for fusion.
我明明在记事本里写的另一个餐馆
I put a different/restaurant in my date book.
我得把我的助手炒掉
I'm firing my assistant.
没事 你好啊 Greg
That's okay. Hi,greg.
我叫你Greg/因为现在我们社会地位平等了
And I call you greg because/we're now social equals.
我叫你蛇蝎女 因为...
I call you cutthroat bitch...
呃 这已经是众人皆知了
well,quod erat demonstrandum.
我还说的拉丁语 我就是要拽给你看
And I speak in latin because I/don't try to hide what an ass I am.
看来你要和我们一起喽?
I assume you'd like to join us?
同桌的话更能方便你观察我们的交流
It'll be easier to observe our/interaction if you're at the same table.
如果我们有桌子的话
If we ever get seated.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
不不 呃...
No,no,I,uh--
现在她要去牺牲色相了/真是抢尽你风头啊
any minute now,she's gonna hit/him in the face with your testicles.
她总是...
She tends/to treat e--
她对待每一件事 都不放过任何机会
she tends to treat every event like/it's the last copterout of saigon.
她就是你的反面
She's the anti-Wilson.
她邪恶无比
She's a force for evil.
她有点讨厌
She has an annoying quality.
也许还不止一点
Perhaps even two.
可惜我也不完美 所以不能要求对方完美
If I was perfect,I would date perfect.
你很享受嘛!
You like that!
她很讨厌 但这是她的长处
It's annoying,but she's good at it.
且慢
Wait a second.
这不仅仅是关于性爱的
This isn't just about the sex.
你喜欢她的性格
You like her personality.
你喜欢她飞扬跋扈
You like that she's conniving.
你喜欢她不计后果
You like that she has no/regard for consequences.
你喜欢她去羞辱别人...
You like that she can humiliate/someone if it serves--
哦我的天
oh,my god.
你爱上的是我
You're sleeping with me.
你得再快点 Roz
I need you to go faster,roz.
再用点力
A little harder.
我在用力了 见鬼
I am going harder,damn it.
如果House医生是对的呢?
What if dr. House was right?
Roz真的经历了巨大转变呢?
And roz did make a radical change?
红斑狼疮是慢性病 但可以治好
Lupus is chronic but treatable.
治愈之后 就会恢复原状?
And with the treatment,it'd/undo the change?
她就会变成我们相遇之前的样子?
She'll be the way she/was before I knew her?
我看不大可能
I don't think it's likely.
这么说你并不确定
Then you don't know for sure.
会有别人让你心动的
You'd find someone else.
没有别的人了
There isn't someone else.
你们约会才三次而已
You've had three dates.
你结婚多久了?
How long have you been married?
12年
12 years.
她还是你心所属吗?
And is she the one?
不然我们怎么会还在一起
We wouldn't still be/together if she weren'T.
我对她的爱一如当初...
I love her as much/nowas the day--
可是你的爱应该更深
well,you should love her more.
相识越久 你的爱就应该越深
The more you know someone,e/more you should love them.
好的 可以了Roz
Okay,that's enough,roz.
很好 你的心脏十分强壮
Okay,your heart's as/strong as a battleship.
这是不是说明House诊断有误?
Yon does this mean dr. House was wrong?
哦 我的腿!
Oh! Oh,my leg!
心脏很健康 说明你错了/精神状态没有改变
Heart's strong enough to prove you/wrong about the change in mental status.
只能说明不是红斑狼疮
Only proves this isn't lupus.
同理 腿疼也说明不是韦格纳病
Just as the leg pain/proves it isn't wegener'S.
腿疼可能是因为神经卡压
Leg pain can be from nerve entrapment.
我们认为有血块
We're thinking blood clot.
做个核磁共振看看有没有血块
Do an mri to look for the clot.
再做个功能核磁共振
Then do an fmri.
- 核磁共振.../- 只能发现未溶解的血块
- An mri alone if/- the clot hasn't dissolved.
但功能核磁共振可以显示/脑缺血部分的卒中迹象
An fmri can show signs of near-ischemic/stroke in post-ischemic parts of the brain.
- 给我10块钱/- 不
- Give me ten bucks./- No.
我没吃午饭
I missed lunch.
- 我以为你去了.../- 我没吃午饭
- I thought you went-/- I missed lunch.
左右脑的活动很对称
good symmetrical/activity in both hemispheres.
尾端看起来也正常
caudal structures look okay.
她没有改变过?
She hasn't changed?
性 毒品 摇滚 还有600条戒律/都在她大脑某处
Sex,drugs,rock and roll,the 600 rules/of god are all in there somewhere.
我们对人的分析过于简单化
We oversimplify people.
大家都习惯这样的思考
It's how the human mind works.
万物非此即彼 凡事都得被定性
Everything's on or off./Everything's got a category.
你不喜欢
You don't like it.
你不喜欢被简单化
You don't wanna be oversimplified.
Roz 动一下你的右腿
Roz move your right leg.
没有人能用10个词来描述自己
No one can describe/themselves in ten words.
我们又何必苛求他人呢?
Why would we want to/hear anyone else do it?
所以你就保持神秘
So you keep it a mystery.
没有人了解你 你就不能被定性
No categories if no one knows anything.
- 你现在是不是在过分简化我呢?/- 不
- Do you think maybe you're over simplifying me now?/- No.
我相信你保持神秘的理由很多/双性恋只是其中之一
I'm sure you have many reasons to keep yourself/a mystery,besides the fact that you're bisexual.
茫然注视这么久 想否认也没人信了
denial would have worked before/the long,vacant stare.
Roz 左腿移动一英尺
Roz,move your left leg just an inch.
讨厌分门别类的人 是因为难以被归类
People who have a problem with boxes/are people who don't fit in them.
你还真是得了House的真传
You've been working for/House for a long time.
不要骂人嘛
No need for name calling.
本想问你是不是准备吃饭时向别人八卦我/不过幸好...
I would ask if this was gonna be/lunch time gossip,but lucky for me--
我才不在乎呢
I don't give a damn.
犹太疯子怎么样了?
How's our mental yentl?
核磁共振没有发现血块
Mri shows no sign of clots.
功能核磁共振也没有发现问题
Fmri shows no problem areas.
重新给她静脉注射
Go restart her iv.
- 有什么问题吗?/- 没事
- What's wrong with it?/- NothinG.
但是被我们折腾了这么久/病人注射时会有疼痛
But like so many procedures we/put patients through,it hurts.
如果她为此而不亦乐乎/图象就会五颜六色
Which,if she's enjoying it,will/show up in pretty colors.
你做功能核磁共振就是因为这个?
This is why you wanted an fmri?
测试证明没有血块 这和诊断相关
It showed she didn't have a blood/clot,which is diagnostically relevant.
也能显示她是否为受虐狂/同样和诊断相关
And it can show if she's become a/masochist-- also diagnostically relevant.
而且还很酷
And it'll be cool.
不想解释我上述分析的合理性/就赶快去做事
Either explain which part of my analysis makes sense or go do it.
一点都不酷
It isn't cool.
抱歉了
I'm sorry.
老天
heavens.
瞧她的中枢边缘系统
Look at her limbic system.
快感中心就像光明节一样亮堂
Pleasure centers are lighting/up like a hanukah bush.
Foreman一定是相当用力啊
Foreman must have a/touch like an elephant.
好了Roz 我们已经有结果了
Okay,roz. We've got what we need.
没错 印象深刻啊
Yes,it was impressive.
Roz 你还好吗?
Roz. You all right?
对不起 我刚才在祈祷
I'm sorry. I was praying.
整个检查过程都是?
All through the procedure?
不...Foreman医生过来道歉时/我知道有坏事要发生了
No. When dr. Foreman apologized,I/knew something bad was gonna happen.
她在祈祷
She was praying.
可以解释大脑活动
Could explain the brain activity.
血压和心率下降 她撑不住了
Bp and heart rate are/dropping. She's crashing.
稳定下来了
She's stabilizing.
扶她起来
Get her up.
再扶 站直了
All the way up. On her feet.
再来一次
Make her do that again.
我们给她用了氟氢可的松和麻黄碱
we started her/onfludrocortisone and ephedrine.
就像人猿星球
It's planet of the apes.
猿猴就是人 人就是猿猴
Apes are the humans,humans are the apes.
疯狂星期三 什么都是反着来的
It's wacky wednesday,opposite day.
站着的时候血压和心率本应该升高 而不是...
When you stand up,your bp and heart/rateare supposed to go up,not--
行了
got it.
那怎么解释她的血尿/膀胱失控 腿疼 精神状态的改变?
So what causes bloody urine,loss of bladder/control,leg pain,altered mental status,
还有血压趋势变化的错误呢?
and pressure-blood in/direction-wrong?
嗜铬细胞瘤
Pheochromocytoma.
尿液中的儿茶酚胺很低/犹太女人没得嗜铬细胞瘤
Low catecholamines in the urine means/no pheochromocytoma in the jewess.
也许是系统性硬皮病
Could be systemic sclerosis.
注意精神状态
Mental status.
她是在祈祷
She was praying.
她感到疼痛
She was in pain.
你现在不觉得她疯了?
You no longer think she's crazy?
我能理解她为什么会被那种生活方式吸引
I can see why she'd be/attracted to that life.
你也喝了那个葡萄酒味的酷乐饮料
You drank/the manishevitz-flavored kool-aid.
我不是赞成 我只是说--
I'm not saying I agree.I'm just saying--
非理性也有理性的基础
that there's a rational/basis for the irrational.
他们身上有我们缺乏的东西
They have something we don't have
比如幻想中的朋友
imaginary friends.
要是烤面包机不能工作/有可能是电线出了问题
If the toaster's not/working,wiring could be bad.
这个比喻怎么解决眼下的问题?
Which debate is that/metaphor supposed to help us with?
心脏的电线问题
Electrical problem in the heart.
她站起来时心律不齐 血液流动节奏混乱/导致血压和心率降低
Arrhythmia messes with the blood flow when/she stands,causes low bp and heart rate.
也能影响到精神状况/所有症状都符合
Could also impact mental/status. Everybody's happy.
给她做个心内电生理检查
Run an ep study of her heart.
看看电线是在哪一块出了问题
Find where the wiring's verklempt.
今早去你住的旅馆了
Went by your hotel this morning.
他们说你搬走了
They told me you moved out.
跟蛇蝎女同居了?
Moved in with C.B.?
不 很显然我是跟你同居了
No,apparently,I moved in with you.
你对我洞察力的反抗正好说明--
The very fact that you're/resisting my insight proves to me--
House 你是对的
House,you're right.
为什么不? 为什么不就跟你约会?
Why not? Why not date you?
这主意太聪明了
It's brilliant.
我们认识对方不知道多少年了/忍受了对方不计其数的糟糕缺点
We've known each other for years,we've put/up with all kinds of crap from each other,
但我们却总是回到对方身边
and we keep coming bacK.
我们就是一对
We're a couple.
我们现在说的是比喻义吗?
Are we still speaking metaphorically?
Amber就是我需要的/你也会同意这一点
Amber is exactly what I/need and you would agree
要不是你沉溺在自大包裹着的/自我嫌恶中
if you weren't mired in self-loathing/topped with a thin crust of megalomania.
你说的可是我最好朋友的妞
That's my best friend's girl/you're talking about.
我之前错了
I was wrong.
House 你是对的
House,you're right.
她不是我
She's not me.
呃 她跟我一样
Well,she is me.
但那不是她的吸引力所在
But that's not why she's attractive.
她是惹人怜惜的我
She's a needy version of me.
很难想象出如此神秘的生物
Hard to imagine such a mythical creature.
我一解雇她你就开始约她了
You started seeing/her right after I fired her.
我四个月前就开始约她了
I started seeing her four months ago.
她告诉Kutner是四星期
She told kutnerit was four weeks.
你骗了我
You lied to me.
我们还赌了钱呢
There was money on the line.
因为我知道你会作何反应/也知道你反正肯定不会给钱
Because I knew how you'd react,and/I knew you wouldn't pay me anyway.
你知道我是对的
You knew that I was right.
她并不可怜
She wasn't needy.
她只是处在... 糟糕的境况下
She was in A... bad situation.
那是不同的
There's a difference.
对你的性欲而言是一回事
Not to your libido.
等一下 等一下
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
你干嘛要这样?
Why are you doing this?
每次我同意了 你就找个新论点
Every time I agree with/you,you find a new argument.
你到底想避免什么?
What are you trying to avoid?
呃 如果在我跟她约会之前/你用这双迷人的眼睛看着我...
Well,if you'd looked at me with those/flashing eyes before I was involved...
这就是生活
C'est la vie. And...
我故意说法语是因为.../你是个混蛋
I use the french/because... you're an ass.
右心房正常 没有心律不齐
right atrium normal,no arrhythmia.
你可以变成个d'har大师了/(D'har大师: 星际迷航中角色)
You can become a d'har master.
不需要再详细解释一下?
Does that require further explanation?
右心室正常
Right ventricle normal.
在大学里我很迷科幻小说--
In college,I was/really into science fiction--
和那些花600块装尖耳朵/用Romulan语骂脏话的读者不同
not like the guys with the $600 prosthetic/ears who could swear in romulan,
我们觉得那是精彩的文学作品
that was embarrassing to the rest of us who/just thought it was good,smart literature.
参加集会
Went to one convention.
二年级我就变成了克林贡王国的/D'har大师
By senior year,I was d'harmaster/in the klingon empire.
我不会跑去信哈西德教派
I'm not gonna become hasidic.
甚至连小小改正一番也不想
I'm not even gonna/becomes lightly more reformed.
冠状窦正常
Coronary sinus normal.
你不可能被什么启发了/却忍住不照着去做
You can't have your eyes opened to/something and not act on it.
我没有被启发 我只是...
I haven't had my eyes opened. I just...
不再以为他们疯了
don't think they're crazy anymore.
那他们肯定是提供了什么东西
Then they have something to offer.
她是个活生生的例子/证明精神正常的人也可以改变
She's living proof that sane/people can make radical changes.
但是House 他认为他能恐吓--
But House,he thinks that/he can bully--
别口出恶言
no loshon hora.
你说什么?
I'm sorry?
我想她是在叫你别东扯西拉了
I think she's telling/you to stop deflecting.
别口出恶言
No loshon hora.
邪恶的话 谣言
Evil tongue. Gossip.
没事的
It's okay.
多亏了镇定剂 你醒了就不记得了
Thanks to the sedative,you/won't remember it.
语言是永恒的
Words are permanent.
总有一天你会说出让你后悔的话
Someday you'll say something that/you'll wish you could take back.
这一束血管正常
This bundle's normal.
所有的血液通路都没问题
Pathways are all clean.
没有心律不齐
No arrhythmias.
要是烤面包机不工作/屋子里的电线线路又都没问题
If the toaster doesn't work and/the wiring in the house is fine,
那就只有可能是城市供电系统了
problem's gotta be in/the city's power grid.
自发性神经紊乱/可能是Riley-Day氏综合征
autonomic nerve disorder could/be riley-day syndrome.
恭喜你结婚
Congratulations on your wedding.
你患上了罕见的遗传性疾病/无法治愈
You have a rare and/incurable degenerative disease.
我准备一下体温调节流汗测试
I'll set up for a/thermo regulatory sweat test.
- 她是双性恋/- 什么?
- She's a bisexual./- What?
我在MRI机器里可以听到他们说话
I could hear them/talking from inside the mri.
听到谁? 我听到了"性"这个字
Hear who? I heard the word sex.
很有意思
It was interesting.
什么很有意思?
what was interesting?
无所谓了
It doesn't matter.
我们是医生/永远不知道什么对病情有影响
We're doctors. We never/know what's gonna matter.
她说了性
She said sex.
要是她醒过来后愿意告诉你...
If she wants to tell/you when she wakes up...
是啊 你还说这些人没有改变你
yeah,these people aren't/gonna change you at all.
我需要你跟Wilson上床
I need you to sleep with Wilson.
早上好
Good morning.
他现在正跟个不恰当的女人交往
He's involved with an/inappropriate woman.
他们家是牧羊人 而Amber家是放牛的?
His people are sheepherders and/Amber's are cattlemen?
他最糟的两个特性合到了一块儿--/他对我的爱和他对可怜兮兮的爱
He's combining two of his worst qualities--/his love for me and his love for need.
作为这家医院的行政主管/你得挽救你的明星肿瘤科医生
As administrator of this hospital,you/have to save your star oncologist.
真希望能帮你 但作为行政主管
Wish I could help,but as administrator,
我得先和财政委员会的人上床
there are some people in accounting/I'm scheduled to sleep with first.
Wilson跟女人交往都是一个类型
Wilson has a pattern with women.
他挽救她们 然后背叛她们/导致了他内疚...
He saves them,then he betrays/them,which then causes guilt...
接着造成他去挽救另外的人
which then causes him to/go save somebody else.
比如 一个医院行政人员/年近四十却没有私生活
For example,a hospital bureaucrat/nearing 40 who has no personal life.
建议你到时候别穿文胸
I suggest you go braless.
我理解你说"上床"的意思是/叫我去跟他谈谈?
I get that "sleep with" is your/way of saying I should talk to him?
不 我就是说上床
No. I really mean sleep with.
你担心的不是他们搞不成/而是他们会成功
You're not worried this relationship/will fail,you're worried it'll succeed.
Wilson就不会再随时听候你召唤了
At Wilson will no longer/beat your beck and call 24/7.
你最好的朋友会改变
That your best friend will change.
人不是想要改变就能改变的
People don't change just because/they wish they could.
但他希望改变这一点就让你不爽!
And it bugs you that he wishes he could!
你永远不会失去这个朋友的 House
You'll never lose your friend,House.
你就是最黏人的家伙
You're the long-distance/runner of neediness.
随着实验室里温度上升/Roz的体温也会上升
as the chAmber heats up,roz's/body temperature should also rise,
会让她流汗 并使粉末变成紫色
making her sweat and/turning the powder purple.
颜色没变说明没有流汗/所以她的神经中枢系统被毁坏了
No change in color means no sweating,which/means her central nervous system is damaged.
我不该看她这个样子
I shouldn't see her like this.
她一出实验室 我们就能下诊断
We could have a diagnosis as soon/as she comes out of the chAmber.
你待在这里会更好
It might be better if you stayed.
这太不尊重她了
It's disrespectful.
我肯定她想象中第一次丈夫看到她裸体/是他们庆祝婚姻缔结之时
I'm sure sure she imagined the first time her husband would/see her bare like this would be celebrating the marriage.
就眼下情况 我想Roz宁愿牺牲名节/也想要你陪在身边
Given the circumstances,I think roz would/sacrifice modesty to have you with her.
求你们了 别那样
Please. Don't do that.
什么? 我觉得你在这里很好/我觉得--
What? I think it's nicethat/you're here.I think--
你觉得...
you think it's sweet...
我在乎她的名节这很甜蜜/但这古老的传统不是那么回事
that I care for her modesty,but that/it's archaic and ultimately irrelevant.
我们的传统并非盲目的仪式/它们...
Our traditions aren't just/blind rituals. They...
有含义
they mean something.
有目的
They have purpose.
我尊重我的妻子
I respect my wife.
我也尊重她的身体
And I respect her body.
她的体温停止上升了
Her body temperature's stopped climbing.
出什么事了?
What's going on?
她开始痉挛 需要急救
she's having a seizure!/We need a crash cart!
还有毛毯! 她快冻僵了
Blankets too! She's freezing.
她本该流汗的 却冻僵了
she was supposed to sweat and she froze.
又回到人猿星球了
return to the planet of the apes.
体温降低导致痉挛
hypothermia caused the seizure.
什么导致体温降低?
What caused the hypothermia?
有可能是感染
it could be an infection.
她体内的白血球数正常
her white blood cell count was fine.
当她被收治入院时
when she was admitted.
有可能在这儿感染了什么
She could have picked something up here.
并发症引起的并发症?
complication on a complication?
身体的反应与它应做的背道而驰
Body's doing the opposite of/what it's supposed to.
她的身体就是Wilson
Her body's Wilson.
我们怎么办?
How do we respond to that?
我们乐意看到他现在很开心
We accept that he's happy.
我们反其道而行之
We do the opposite.
那你想要我们怎么样/把病人送回家去?
So you want us to/what,send the patient home?
感染...
Infection...
说明有什么东西入侵了身体/本来应该被驱除出去的
means that something's been added to the/body,something that should be expelled.
反过来是什么?
What's the opposite of that?
身体缺乏什么东西
Something missing from the body.
可能是某种酶或荷尔蒙
Could be an enzyme or a hormone.
皮质醇 可能是Addison氏综合症
Cortisol. Could be addison's.
符合
It fits.
所有症状
Every symptom.
我去做个皮质醇刺激测试
I'll run a cortisol stimulation test.
你确定她不是想把你带回巢穴/然后把你倒吊起来
Are you sure she doesn't wanna just take/you back to her lair,hang you upside down,
把她的卵植入你体内?
and deposit her eggs in you?
好高明的易容术 House
Excellent disguise,House.
你们俩的是认真的?
You two are really that serious?
她很漂亮 又很风趣
She's pretty. She's funny.
也许她是有点太...
Maybe she's a little more...
邪恶?
evil?
比我要更野心勃勃一些
Aggressive than you'd expect from me.
但我很快乐
But I'm happy.
我就不能先享受一下那种感觉吗?
Can't I just enjoy what that/feels like for a while?
当你给病人判死刑时/他们大多满怀信任地望着你
How many people have looked at you trustingly/while you gave them a fatal prognosis,
但你知道告诉他们真相更好
but you knew it was/kinder to tell them the truth?
Amber强迫性地关注第一名
Amber compulsively/looks out for number one.
你强迫性地关注身边人
You compulsively look out for/the person that you're with.
你的需求会喂饱她的需求
Your needs are gonna feed her needs
直到最后仅剩地板上/一个Wilson形状的粉笔轮廓
until all that's left is a Wilson/chalk outline on the floor.
抱歉
Sorry.
那个皮质醇很不错
That cortisol stuff is great.
对所有症状都起作用吗?
Does it work on everything?
我猜你感觉好些了?
I take it you're feeling better.
还是有些虚弱 但的确好些了
Oh,still weak. But yeah.
你肯定累坏了
You must be so tired.
你应该回家去睡一觉
You should go home and get some sleep.
我会陪着你的
I'll stay.
我从没告诉过你 但你比Silver夫人/暗示的要帅多了
I never told you,but you are much better/looking than mrs. Silver led me to expect.
她不太喜欢我
She never liked me.
我八岁时在叔叔的婚礼上/吐到她鞋子上了
When I was eight,I threw up on/her shoes at my uncle's wedding.
你的腹部有些肿
Your abdomen's a little swollen.
很严重吗?
Is it serious?
不好说
It's hard to say.
有时候可能是肝出了问题/我们得检查一下
Sometimes it can meana liver/issue. We'll have to test.
噢 我头晕...
oh,dizzinessis/getting--
她快休克了/给我一升生理盐水
She's going into shock. I/need another liter of saline.
两个单位的浓红 作交叉配血
Type and cross two units.
她怎么了?
What's happening to her?
内出血
She's bleeding internally.
她在说"shema"/(希伯来语祈祷的话)
She's saying the shema.
她觉得自己快死了
She thinks she's dying.
磁共振结果显示你有内出血/但是不知道出血点在哪里
The mri shows you're bleeding/internally,but not where it's coming from.
输的血不能保证你一直病情平稳
The blood can only keep/you stable for so long.
最好的选择是行剖腹探查术
Our best option is to/open you up and search.
你能治好对吗?
But you can fix it?
如果能找到出血点的话
If we find the leak.
找到了出血点 就知道是什么病了吗?
You find the bleeding,you/find the disease?
不是
No.
但能保证你活到House医生/查清你得的是什么病
But it could keep you alive long enough so/dr. House can find what's wrong with you.
不
No.
我不想做这个手术...
I don't want to have the surgery...
这是你唯一的活路
it's the only chance you've got.
日落之前我不想做手术
I don't want to have the/surgery until after sunset.
说不定我就要死了
I'm probably gonna die anyway.
我只想和我丈夫共度这个安息日
I just wanna share one/shabbat with my husband.
Roz 求你了
Roz,please.
希伯来圣经教诲我们/永远不要放弃生命
The torah commands us to preserve life.
我用了38年找寻到了我想要的
I waited 38 years to find what I wanted.
再等八个小时不算什么
I can wait another eight hours.
然后听天由命 好吗?
I'll leave the rest to god,okay?
我让犹太法师劝过她了
I had a rabbi call.
可她一意孤行
She's adamant.
她不是性虐狂
She's not a masochist.
她是不想活了
She's suicidal.
干得漂亮 Chase
Nice work,chase.
啊 我该找双胞胎法师劝她的
Yeah. I should have had twin rabbis call.
能走了吗?
Can I go?
我们需要你
We need you.
我们只有几个小时来搞定/不是好几天
So instead of a few days we now/have a few hours to figure this out.
干得漂亮 Chase
Nice work,chase.
你们为什么需要我?
Why do you need me?
说"干得漂亮 Chase"的时候/你要不在场就没意思了
Saying,"nice work,chase"when/you're not here is pointless.
说真的 我们需要你
Seriously,we need you.
可能是肋骨畸形导致动脉扭曲/要做X线摄片确定
We should x-ray for malformations of the/rib that could cause arterial twisting.
但畸形不会导致血尿
Malformations don't cause bloody urine.
她不是想自杀
She's not suicidal.
她想和她的丈夫开始新的生活
She made a commitment to/a new life with her husband
她想开始有意义的人生
and she wants one/meaningful experience in that life.
她和那男人相识没多久
She just met the guy.
Taub也才碰见她
taub just met her.
然后就这么相爱了/他已经准备好在她死后
And he's already so in/love,he's ready to let her die
把她带回母星球 埋葬在熔岩海里
and take her back to the home planet/for a buria lin the lava sea of tormiad.
也许他就是这种人
It's who he might be.
她在用心感应/她无法再拥有的时光
She's connecting with all the/years she's not gonna have.
去感应倒不如去拥有
Better way of connecting to those/years is to actually have them.
想争取时间?
You want more time?
约书亚祈求上帝让时间停留在白天
Joshua got god to/make the sun stand still.
没理由上帝不能让时间走快一点
No reason god can't speed it up.
说的上帝 当然我指的是你
And,by god,I of course mean you.
我就说我们需要你嘛
Told you we needed you.
太阳落山了 Roz
It's sun down,roz.
我们要带你回房间去吃圣餐/准备好了吗?
We're taking you back to your room/for your candle light dinner. Ready?
一 二 三
One,two three.
是不是太早了
It's too early.
药物使你对时间的感觉模糊了
Your sense of time is/off because of the medication.
愿主保佑 Roz
Good shabbos,roz.
所以你祈祷和吃完圣餐/我们就可以做手术了?
So you pray,scarf down some/challah,then we can do this?
你想见我?
You wanted to see me?
你就来了
And you came.
我相信会有什么有趣的事儿
I feel pretty confident/it'll be something interesting.
搞定了这病例 工作就是你的
Solve this case and the job is yours.
是不是有条叫做"甩掉Wilson"/的附加条款呢?
Is there a "drop Wilson"/clause attached to this?
签统一格式的合同
Standard contract all employees sign.
为什么你非要认为我动机不纯呢?
Why do you have to believe I/have an ulterior motive?
跟吸毒的妓女为了毒品/跟人上床是一个道理
For the same reason I believe that/crack whores can have sex for crack.
我这一生中
All my life
一直以为我要在爱和尊重之间选择
I thought I had to choose/between love and respect.
而我选择了尊重
And I chose respect.
但是跟Wilson在一起...
And with Wilson...
我知道我两者都拥有了
I know what it's like to have both.
这比当你的下属更宝贵
And that beats a fellowship.
可能是弥漫性血管内凝血
Could be D.I.C.
你变了
You've changed.
但愿如此
I hope so.
血小板计数正常/排除了弥漫性血管内凝血
Normal platelet count rules out D.I.C.
猜得不错
Good try though.
我发现了个包虫囊 可能会...
I read that a/hydatid cyst could--
可能会感染肺 但不会感染膀胱
would affect the lungs,not the bladder.
又测了一遍白细胞计数 正常
Tested her white/cell count again. Normal.
还要多久能给她做手术?
How long till weget to cut her open?
我离开的时候他还在唱什么eshet的东东
When I left,he was/still singing eshet something.
那是丈夫在为他的妻子祈福
The husband's blessing of his wife.
他称她为上帝赐予的最珍贵的礼物
He calls her eshet/chayil,woman of valor.
"力量和荣耀是她的衣裳 她笑对人生"
"Strength and honor are her/clothing. She laughs at the future."
因为她就是个白痴
Because she's an idiot.
小肠扭转可能会导致出血
Volvulus of the small/intestine could cause bleeding.
那会有便秘
She would have had constipation.
她的价值也算不上"比珍珠更珍贵"
Her value isn't "beyond pearls" either.
因为死人没什么价值可言
'Cause dead people have no value.
真红细胞增多症
Polycythemia vera.
那样红细胞计数应该是高的
Rbc count would be higher.
我要那光照耀我的脸
I need to bring the light to my face.
血小板减少症
thrombocytopenia.
- 要是是自身免疫病的话.../- 滴度正常
- If it's autoimmune-/- titers were normal.
帕金森病可以解释低体温
Parkinson's would/explain the hypothermia.
但解释不了血尿
Not the bloody urine.
那女人不光是个性虐者/她还是个伪君子
The woman's not just a/masochist,she's a hypocrite.
追求生命的戒律高于一切
The commandment to preserve/life comes before all others.
也说明了她不是个受虐者
Actually means she's not a masochist.
她并不守所有的戒律 只追随她所喜欢的
She's not following all the/rules,just the ones that please her.
对 就这么神经兮兮来到医院/鼓吹宗教胜过生命
Right,she walked in crazy and/explained how ritual trumps living,
你还觉得这是美好的生活方式
and you decide it's a/beautiful life style.
我知道
I know.
她错了
She's wrong.
如果再没有--
But if/there's nothing more--
唯一的意义只在此岸
then the only meaning is here.
但是如果她认为上帝在守候她
but if she thinks god is there for her,
如果一生坚信上帝与她同在
if she lives her life believing/that god is there--
那她就死定了
then she dies.
万物并不因人的意志而存在
Things aren't where we want them to be/just because we want them to be there.
这也不意味着它们就在原地老实待着
Of course,that doesn't/mean they're where they should be.
让那个犹太人拦下
Stop that jew.
Chase不喜欢在安息日干活
Chase hates working on shabbos.
给他帮个小忙 扶她站起来
Gonna make this easier/for him. Stand her up.
她脚不好使
She doesn't do so well on her feet.
我也是
Neither do I.
扶她站起来
Stand her up.
你可以在浸礼池前告诉/所有的女士这个故事
You can tell all the ladies at/the mikvah about this.
你干了什么?
what did you do?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
把手放在这里 用力压
Put your hand here. Press hard.
你有肾下垂
You have nephroptosis.
也就是"游走肾"
Also known as "floating kidney."
她的肾就像个晃晃悠悠的吊灯
The kidney's like a chandelier.
黏在肠壁和血管做的天花板上
It's attached to a ceiling/of intestines and blood vessels.
但是创造你的上帝自以为是/用根劣质的链子挂你的肾
But your contractor--think you know who/he is-- he hung it with a cheap chain.
就这么晃晃悠悠的挂了好多年
It's been hanging sloppy for years.
最终被摇松了
Finally something shook it loose.
在这之后 每次你站起来/你的肾都会下坠几厘米
After that,every time you stood,your/kidney dropped a few centimeters,
导致了你所有的症状
caused all your symptoms.
所有的扫描都没有发现
None of the scans picked it up.
因为做扫描的时候病人都是躺着的
Because we do scans with/patients lying down.
她做手术的时候也是躺着的
She'd have been lyin down in surgery too.
所以从来没被发现过
Never have found it.
她撑不过去可能也很大
Good chance she'd never come out.
她会好吗?
She'll be all right?
超声确诊/告诉Chase把她那肾挂回去
Ultrasound to confirm,then tell chase/to put the kidney back on the shelf.
出血点就在附近
The bleed will be nearby.
就这样?
That'S...it?
好运
Mazel tov.
几个小时的手术之后/你想生出14个小孩都行
Couple hours surgery,you'll be/ready to push out those 14 children.
你两种都做对吗?
You do it both ways,right?
什么?
What?
超声--站着和躺着的你都做
The ultra sound--you do/it standing up and lying down.
我还会是说什么呢?
What else would I mean?
我想通了 你给我找个女性替身/这还不算烂到家
I've decided you could do worse/than a female proxy for me.
你承认人会改变了吗?
So you're going to/acknowledge that people can change?
不是
No.
- 你觉得是我变了或是Amber变了?/- 不是
- You think I've changed or Amber's changed?/- Nope.
那就是你变了
Then you've changed.
如果你真的变了/最好不要再追到楼下来 试着改变我
If you do change,can it be the part of you/that chases me down halls,trying to change me?
你知道这意味着什么吗?
Do you know what this means?
你选约会对象的眼光不错
That you made one good dating choice.
时空的连续性被拆散了
The fabric of the/space/time continuum could unravel.
我想我的世界更丰富了
My world could expand.
我想我可以维系一段/除了你之外的长久关系了
I could form a long-term/connection that isn't with you.
照你惯用的阴暗理论来解释这个世界
And since you put the darkest/possible construction on everything,
你可能失去我这个朋友
you could end up losing a friend.
这些你全都心知肚明
You you've thought of all this.
你还是接受了
And yet... you're going along with it.
你是不是要... 自我牺牲?
Are you being... self-sacrificing?
我会牺牲实验室里的老鼠/我会牺牲一只苍蝇
I'll sacrifice a lab/rat,I'll sacrifice a fly,
我会牺牲200块钱在赛马上
and I'll sacrifice $200 on/a mudder at monmouth park.
我从不自我牺牲
I don't sacrifice self.
安息日平安 Wilson
Shabbat shalom,Wilson.
安息日平安 House
Shabbat shalom,House.